Guide to the Brooklyn Historical Society newspaper collection ARC.258
Brooklyn Historical Society
Brooklyn Historical Society newspaper collection
1783-2017
1820-2005
Brooklyn Historical Society
ARC.258
210.75 Linear Feet in 59 boxes, 252 bound volumes, and 87 reels of microfilm
The collection is primarily composed of newspapers published in Brooklyn, New York, dating from the 18th century to 2016. It also includes a selection of newspapers published in Queens, Long Island, upstate New York, and New Jersey. In addition to paper editions, the collection includes microfilm copies of certain publications.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The newspapers were found in collection, with the exception of the March 1, 1873 issue of the Kings County Gazette, which was the gift of Martin Fishman, 2001.
Online Availability note
Full-text searchable versions of the Brooklyn Daily Eagle, the Brooklyn Evening Star, the Brooklyn Evening Daily Star, and the Long Island Star are freely available online.
Arrangement
The newspapers are arranged alphabetically by title.
Note on additional newspapers
Please note that this collection does not includes newspapers which are currently being held at our off-site storage facility.
Related Materials
Chandos Fulton notes on the history of Brooklyn newspapers, 1863-1864 (1973.223)
Political news clippings scrapbook, 1894 (1977.216)
Brooklyn Eagle records, 1887-1955 (1977.226)
Long Islander clippings collection, 1847-1889 (1985.040)
New-York Mercury issue, 1782 (1985.060)
Long Island Traveler scrapbook collection, 1897-1911 (1985.068)
Park Slope Civic Council records, 1938-1965 (1991.041)
Thomas N. Schroth and Raymond A. Schroth, S.J. Brooklyn Eagle collection (ARC.093)
Brooklyn neighborhood associations and civic organizations publications, 1881-2010 (ARC.167)
Elizabeth Feldhusen collection of Brooklyn ephemera, circa 1920s-1992 (ARC.299)
World War I political cartoons collection, 1916-1918 (CBHM.0011)
Scope and Contents
The collection is primarily composed of newspapers published in Brooklyn, New York, dating from the 18th century to 2016. In addition to paper editions, the collection includes microfilm copies of certain publications.
Geographically, the newspapers cover the numerous neighborhoods of Brooklyn, as well the other boroughs of New York City (Manhattan, Queens, Staten Island, and the Bronx), Long Island (Suffolk and Nassau Counties), and parts of upstate New York and New Jersey. The collection also includes issues of The Liberator, an abolitionist newspaper which was published in Boston, Massachusetts.
Some newspapers were published for specific communities (African-Americans, Caribbean-Americans, Catholics, Jewish-Americans, the military) or specific topics (business, real estate, antiques, computers, etc.).
One newspaper of note is The Christian Union, which was edited by Henry Ward Beecher.
For a complete list of newspapers included in the collection, please see the inventory below. Please note that this collection does not include newspapers which are currently being held at our off-site storage facility. For a listing of these holdings, please contact BHS library staff at: library@brooklynhistory.org
Abolitionists -- New York (State) -- Kings County; African Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; African American newspapers -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Albany (N.Y.); Antiques -- New York (State) -- Long Island; Babylon (N.Y.); Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y); Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); Bensonhurst (New York, N.Y.); Borough Park (New York, N.Y.); Bronx (New York, N.Y.); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Commerce; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Economic conditions; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Intellectual life; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Politics and government; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social conditions; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Social life and customs; Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.); Brownsville (New York, N.Y.); Bushwick (New York, N.Y.); Canarsie (New York, N.Y.); Caribbean Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Carroll Gardens (New York, N.Y.); Catholics -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.); Cobble Hill (New York, N.Y.); Community development -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Community newspapers -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Coney Island (New York, N.Y.); Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); Downtown Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); East Flatbush (New York, N.Y.); East New York (New York, N.Y.); East Norwich (N.Y.); Far Rockaway (New York, N.Y.); Finnish Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Flatbush (New York, N.Y.); Flushing (New York, N.Y.); Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.); Freeport (N.Y.); Goshen (N.Y.); Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.); Hempstead (N.Y.); Hispanic Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Huntington (N.Y.); Italian Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Jamaica (New York, N.Y.); Jewish newspapers -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Kingston (N.Y.); Latvian Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Long Island (N.Y.); Manhattan (New York, N.Y.); Neighborhoods -- New York (State) -- Kings County; New Brunswick (N.J.); New York Naval Shipyard; Newspapers; Northport (N.Y.); Norwegian Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Parents -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Polish Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Port Jefferson (N.Y.); Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.); Queens County (N.Y.); Queens (New York, N.Y.); Real estate business -- New York (State) -- Kings County -- Periodicals; Red Hook (New York, N.Y.); Rockville Centre (N.Y.); Russian Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Schools -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Sheepshead Bay (New York, N.Y.); Staten Island (New York, N.Y.); Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.); Swedish Americans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Westchester County (N.Y.); Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.); Windsor Terrace (New York, N.Y.); Beecher, Henry Ward; United States Maritime Service. Sheepshead Bay Training Station
- Afro Times, July 3 - August 14, 1999; June 30, 2007 (Box 1)
  General
  African-American community newspaper
- Antidote, The (Albany, New York), February 6, 1828 (Box 19)
- Antiques and Collectibles, January - December 1983 (Box 1)
  "Serving Brooklyn, Queens, and Long Island"; Missing September 1983
- Bay News, April 22, 1985 (Box 19)
- Bay News, July 5 - August 16, 1999 (Box 1)
- Bay News (nine bound volumes), January 2001 - October 2003 (Volume Library gallery shelf 29.1.F)
- Bay News (one bound volume), November-December 2003 (Volume Library gallery shelf 29.1.G)
- Bay Ridge Courier (nine bound volumes), 2001-2005 (Volume Library gallery shelf 29.1.G)
  Missing July-December 2001
- Bay Ridge Shopper, The, May 1984 (Box 51)
- Bensonhurst Paper, The, August 6, 1998 (Box 2)
- Blacks and Computers, circa 1996 (Box 1)
- Bohack News, November 1951 - January 1957 (Box 2)
  Published by Bohack's grocery store; Pages 3 and 4 only
- Boro Park Community News, August 31 - December 1, 1983; January - May 2005 (Box 1)
- Brooklyn, April 1931 (Box 51)
- Brooklyn!!, Summer 2005 (Box 1)
- Brooklyn Advocate (one bound volume), September 12, 1833 - April 30, 1835 (Volume 1)
- Brooklyn Business Trends, February-April, October 2011; March-May 2012 (Box 1)
- Brooklyn Citizen (microfilm), 1887-1889 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Brooklyn City News, November 1859 - December 1860 (Box 3)
- Brooklyn City News (two bound volumes), 1861 (Box 53)
- Brooklyn City News (two bound volumes), 1862 (Box 54)
- Brooklyn City News, March 10, 1862 (Box 2)
- Brooklyn City News (two bound volumes), 1863 (Box 52)
- Brooklyn Community News, September 28, 1998; February 8, 1999 (Box 1)
  "Serving Downtown Brooklyn, Clinton Hill, Fort Greene, Bedford-Stuyvesant, Prospect Heights, Crown Heights, Wingate, East Flatbush, Brownsville, Bushwick, Starrett City"
- Brooklyn Courier, November 2-15, 2012 (Box 1)
  "Serving Gowanus, Park Slope, Prospect Heights, Windsor Terrace, Brooklyn Heights, DUMBO, Metrotech, Boerum Hill, Carroll Garderns, Cobble Hill, Red Hook, Williamsburg, and Greenpoint"; This issue concerns Hurricane Sandy.
- Brooklyn Daily Bulletin, The, October 1992 (Box 2)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle (microfilm), March 2, 1846 - January 31, 1848 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle (one bound volume), July-December 1850 (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle (one bound volume), July-December 1858 (Box 4)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, April 25, September 21, 1861; March 28, April 1, June 23, October 6, October 7, 1862 (Box 2)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle (one bound volume), July-December 1871 (Box 5)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle (one bound volume), January-June 1873 (Box 6)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle - Consolidation supplement, January 2, 1898 (Box 55)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle (microfilm), January – December 1907 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, December 31, 1911 (Box 56)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle - Development Series, April - May 1912 (Box 2)
  Includes Brooklyn Planning Section, Industrial Section, Long Island Planning Section, and Outdoor Life Section
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle - 75th Anniversary publication, October 26, 1916 (Box 51)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, Feb. 20, November 9, 17, 1998; Feb. 16, 1999; July 1 - August 23, 1999; April 27, 2000 (Box 1)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, October 2002 - May 2003 (Box 7)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, June - December 2003 (Box 8)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, January - May 2004 (Box 9)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, June - September 2004 (Box 10)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, October-December 2004 (Box 11)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, January 3 - June 30, 2005 (Box 2)
  Includes April 21, 2005 issue of Brooklyn Eagle
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, July 1 - November 31, 2005 (Box 20)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, December 1, 2005 - February 28, 2006 (Box 21)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, March 1 - June 15, 2006 (Box 22)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, June 16 - September 29, 2006 (Box 23)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, October 2, 2006 - January 31, 2007 (Box 24)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, February 1 - April 30, 2007 (Box 25)
  Includes April 5, 2007 issue of Brooklyn Eagle
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, May 1 - July 31, 2007 (Box 26)
  Includes May 10, May 24, June 21, 2007 issues of Brooklyn Eagle
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, August 1 - October 31, 2007 (Box 27)
  Includes August 16 and September 20, 2007 issues of Brooklyn Eagle
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, November 1, 2007 - February 29, 2008 (Box 28)
  Includes December 20, 2007 issue of Brooklyn Eagle
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, March 1 - May 30, 2008 (Box 29)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, June 2 - August 28, 2008 (Box 30)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, September 2 - October 31, 2008 (Box 31)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, November 2008 - October 2009 (Box 12)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, November 2009 - June 2010 (Box 13)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, July-September 2010 (Box 14)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, October-December 2010 (Box 15)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, January-March 2011 (Box 16)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, April-July 2011 (Box 17)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, August 2011 - February 2012 (Box 18)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, February - August 2012 (Box 34)
- Brooklyn Daily Eagle, September 2012 - January 2013; March 2017 - April 2017 (Box 32)
- Brooklyn Daily Program, March 21, 1870 (Box 19)
- Brooklyn Daily Times (microfilm), January 3 – June 30, 1859 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Brooklyn Daily Times (microfilm), January 2, 1861 – June 30, 1865 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Brooklyn Daily Times (microfilm), January 2 – December 31, 1866 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Brooklyn Daily Times (microfilm), July 1 – December 31, 1867 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Brooklyn Daily Times (microfilm), January 2, 1868 – June 29, 1872 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Brooklyn Daily Times (microfilm), January 2, 1873 – August 30, 1893 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Brooklyn Daily Times (microfilm), January 2, 1894 – December 30, 1911 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Brooklyn Daily Union (one bound volume), September 14, 1863 - September 13, 1864 (Box 33)
  Includes letter from publishers and list of original subscribers
- Brooklyn Daily Union, April 15, 1865; January 19, 1866 (Box 31)
- Brooklyn Downtown Star, February 17, 2005 - August 25, 2005 (Box 32)
  Not a complete run; Covering Brooklyn neighborhoods of Downtown Brooklyn, Fort Greene, Clinton Hill, Brooklyn Heights, DUMBO, Prospect Heights, and Boerum Hill
- Brooklyn Downtown Star, September 22, 2005 - January 26, 2006; April 5, 2007 - July 30, 2009 (Box 35)
- Brooklyn Downtown Star, August 6, 2009 - March 27, 2011 (Box 36)
- Brooklyn Downtown Star, March 31, 2011 - December 27, 2012 (Box 37)
- Brooklyn Downtown Star, January 3, 2013 - November 19, 2015; September-December 2016 (Box 38)
- Brooklyn Eagle, September 2-6, 2013 (Box 38)
- Brooklyn Eagle, October 2016 - March 2017 (Box 51)
- Brooklyn Evening Star, July 21, 1841; November 1, 1859 (Box 31)
- Brooklyn Free Press, December 7, 1987; January 28, 1991 (Box 38)
- Brooklyn Free Press, November 29 - December 5, 2002 (Box 31)
- Brooklyn Graphic, The, July 5 - August 16, 1999 (Box 38)
- Brooklyn Graphic, The (eight bound volumes), January 2001 - December 2005 (Volume Library gallery shelf 29.1.G)
- Brooklyn Heights Courier, October 8-21, 1990; July 12 - August 16, 1999; April 24, 2000 (Box 38)
  Covers Brooklyn Heights and Downtown Brooklyn
- Brooklyn Heights Courier (eight bound volumes), January 2001 - December 2003 (Volume Library gallery shelf 29.1.G)
- Brooklyn Heights Courier (eleven bound volumes), January 2004 - December 2006 (Volume Library gallery shelf 29.1.H)
- Brooklyn Heights Courier, April 15-21, 2011 (Box 38)
- Brooklyn Heights Paper, January 1999 - November 2004 (Box 31)
  Not a complete run
- Brooklyn Heights Press (microfilm), 1939-1959 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Brooklyn Heights Press, February-August 1961 (Box 56)
- Brooklyn Heights Press, May-June 1961 (Box 39)
- Brooklyn Heights Press, January 6 - December 22, 1983 (Box 31)
  Continued by Brooklyn Heights Press and Cobble Hill News
- Brooklyn Heights Press and Cobble Hill News, April 29, July 1 - August 13, 1999; April 27, 2000; October 23, 2003; August 15, 2013 (Box 38)
- Brooklyn, Inc, July and October 1987 (Box 56)
  The monthly business section of The Phoenix
- Brooklyn Jewish Week, The, November 27, 1987 (Box 39)
- Brooklyn Journal of Arts and Urban Affairs, November 1976 (Box 31)
- Brooklyn Journal, The, August 1980; April 1983 (Box 51)
- Brooklyn Journal, 1996; May 31, 1999 (Box 31)
  "Paper of Arts and Urban Affairs"
- Brooklyn Journal of Arts and Urban Affairs, April 11-18, 2002 (Box 31)
- Brooklyn Magazine, Fall 1976 (Box 51)
- Brooklyn Paper, 1983-1988; October 2003 - February 2006 (Box 31)
  Not a complete run; Includes Cobble Hill, Carroll Gardens, and Downtown Brooklyn editions; Include articles on BHS
- Brooklyn Parent, August 1990 (Box 38)
  "Park Slope, Brooklyn Heights, Carroll Gardens, Cobble Hill, Boerum Hill"; Includes article on BHS
- Brooklyn Progress, 1976-1982 (Box 38)
  Previously published as Downtown Brooklyn (1974-1976); Brooklyn Chamber of Commerce and Downtown Brooklyn Development Corporation; Not a complete run
- Brooklyn Progress, 1982-1988 (Box 31)
- Brooklyn Progress - '88 Supplement, September 12, 1988 (Box 38)
- Brooklyn's Progress, July 1999 - January 2006 (Box 38)
- Brooklyn Progress, September 2015; September-December 2016 (Box 38)
- Brooklyn Record, June 24 - December 30, 1983 (Box 39)
- Brooklyn Record, December 8, 1995; March 29 - November 22, 1996; July 23 - August 13, 1999, May-June 2002 (Box 39)
  Includes article on BHS
- Brooklyn Schools, 1987 (Box 40)
- Brooklyn Tenant, The, September 1976 (Box 40)
  Published by the Flatbush Tenants Council. "Servicing Flatbush, Midwood, Kings Highway, Gravesend and Sheepshead Bay".
- Brooklyn Times, The, January 6 - December 29, 1983 (Box 40)
- Brooklyn Today, November 16, 1972 (Box 42)
- Brooklyn Union, The, April 10, 1867 (Box 31)
- Canarsie Courier, January - August 1983 (Box 50)
  "Canarsie, Marine Park, Mill Basin, Georgetown, Gerritsen Beach, Bergen Beach, Kings Plaza, Sheepheads Bay, Flatlands, Flatbush, East New York, Spring Creek"
- Canarsie Courier, August - December 1983 (Box 40)
- Canarsie Courier, July 22 - August 12, 1999; November 7, 2002; October 30, 2003 - March 26, 2004 (Box 40)
- Canarsie Courier, May 6, 2004 - October 13, 2005 (Box 41)
- Canarsie Courier, November 24, 2005 - May 11, 2006; December 27, 2007 - December 18, 2008 (Box 42)
- Canarsie Courier, January 1, 2009 - August 19, 2010 (Box 43)
- Canarsie Courier, September 2, 2010 - March 29, 2012 (Box 44)
- Canarsie Courier, April 5, 2012 - July 13, 2013; August - November 2015; September 2016 - March 2017 (Box 45)
- Canarsie Digest (eight bound volumes), 2001-2005 (Volume Library gallery shelf 29.1.H)
- Caribbean Life (Brooklyn edition) (one bound volume), January-February 2001 (Volume Library gallery shelf 29.1.H)
- Caribbean Life (Brooklyn edition) (two bound volumes), March-June 2001 (Volume Library gallery shelf 30.1.D)
- Caribbean Life (Brooklyn and Staten Island edition) (thirteen bound volumes), July 2001 - December 2003 (Volume Library gallery shelf 30.1.D)
- Caribbean Life (Manhattan, Bronx, and Westchester edition) (sixteen bound volumes), January 2001 - August 2005 (Volume Library gallery shelf 30.1.D)
- Caribbean Life (Queens and Long Island edition) (ten bound volumes), January 2001 - September 2003 (Volume Library gallery shelf 30.1.D)
- Caribbean Life (Queens and Long Island edition) (nine bound volumes), October 2003 - December 2005 (Volume Library gallery shelf 30.1.E)
- Carroll Gardens/Cobble Hill Courier, July 19 - August 16, 1999; April 24, 2000 (Box 45)
- Carroll Gardens/Cobble Hill Courier (seven bound volumes), January 2001 - June 2002 (Volume Library gallery shelf 30.1.E)
- Carroll Gardens/Cobble Hill Courier (eighteen bound volumes), July 2002 - December 2005 (Volume Library gallery shelf 30.1.F)
- Chat, The (Sag Harbor, New York) (microfilm), May 7, 1921 – January 1942 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Children's Times, The, February 1998 (Box 42)
  Regarding Brooklyn public schools
- Christian Union, The (New York, New York), March-July 1874 (Box 55)
  Edited by Henry Ward Beecher.
- Christian Union, The (New York, New York), January-June 1882 (Box 57)
- Civic News (Park Slope Civic Council) (nineteen bound volumes), 1938-1991 (Volume Library gallery shelf 21.1.C)
- Commercial Advertiser, The (New York), July 1, 1899 (Box 19)
- Community Advocate, Spring 1988 (Box 45)
  Southern Brooklyn Community Organization and the Ocean Parkway Community Development Corporation
- Coney Island Times (one bound volume), 1927 (Volume 1)
- Coney Island Times Pictorial, June 1925 (Box 56)
- Corrector, The, August 3, 1822 – December 1911 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Courier Homes (eight bound volumes), 1996-2006 (Volume Library gallery level 29.1.F)
- Courier-Life Wedding Guides (one bound volume), 2001-2002 (Volume Library gallery level 31.1.H)
- Courier-Life Supplements (one bound volume), 1996-1997 (Volume Library gallery level 31.1.H)
- Crown Heights News, December 1994 (Box 39)
- Daily Star (Long Island City, New York) (microfilm), 1882-1926 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Darbininkas, November-December 1987 (Box 56)
  Lithuanian language
- Der Yid, April 10, 1987 (Box 39)
  Hebrew language. "Voice of American Orthodox Jewry".
- Downtown Brooklyn, March 1972 - December 1973 (Box 51)
  Published by the Downtown Brooklyn Development Association
- Downtown Brooklyn, August 1974 - February 1976 (Box 38)
  Becomes Brooklyn Progress. Published by the Downtown Brooklyn Development Association.
- East New Yorker, October 1974 (Box 56)
  East New York Development Corporation
- East Norwich Enterprise (23 bound volumes), September 11, 1880 - February 25, 1925; Some of the papers are in fragile condition and some have clippings cut out of the pages. (Volume East Norwich Enterprise, Vol 1-23)
- Eastern District News, June 6, 1986 (Box 56)
- Eastern District News, July 1986 (Box 39)
  Williamsburg, Greenpoint, and Bushwick
- Edgewood Echo, The, June 1893 - February 1894 (Box 55)
  Published in Blythebourne, today the Borough Park neighborhood of Brooklyn.
- El Pitirre, June-August 1991 (Box 51)
  Latino community of Williamsburg. Spanish and English language.
- Flatbush Life, May 9 and December 26, 1983 (Box 39)
- Flatbush Life, July 5 - August 16, 1999 (Box 45)
- Flatbush Life (seven bound volumes), January 2001 - December 2005 (Volume Library gallery shelf 30.1.F)
- Flatbush Life, June 16, 2006 (Box 45)
- Flushing Daily Times (microfilm), October 11, 1866 - September 9, 1925 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Flushing Journal Weekly (microfilm), May 14, 1842 – June 8, 1907 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Fort Greene/Clinton Hill Courier (four bound volumes), April-December 2005 (Volume Library gallery shelf 30.1.F)
- Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper (New York), December 23, 1876 (Box 56)
  Brooklyn Theatre Fire
- Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper (New York), June 2, 1883 (Box 31)
- Gaslight Gazette (Park Slope), September 22, 1971 (Box 42)
- Greenline, March 1989 (Box 56)
  North Brooklyn Community News
- Greenpoint Gazette, January 4 - December 27, 1983; April 9, 23, 1985; January 5, 1993 (Box 46)
- Heaving Line, May 1944 (Box 55)
  "Published by and for the men of the Sheepshead Bay Training Station"
- Heights-Hill Shopper, The, June 1984 (Box 51)
- Hempstead Inquirer (microfilm), January 1, 1853 - January 27, 1949 (Cabinet Microfilm)
  Previously The Inquirer
- Hoboe Pycckoe Cлobo, December 20, 1988 (Box 56)
  Russian language
- Home Reporter and Sunset News, April - July 1998; July 2 - August 13, 1999 (Box 46)
  Bay Ridge and Sunset Park
- Il Progresso, December 10, 1988 (Box 42)
  Italian language.
- Inquirer, The (Village of Hempstead), August 12, 1831 (Box 19)
  Becomes the Hempstead Inquirer
- Jamaica Queens Voice (microfilm), January 1967 – December 1968 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Jewish People, September 13, 1976 (Box 55)
- Jewish Press, December 11, 1987 (Box 42)
- Kings County Rural Gazette (Flatbush, New York), March 1, 1873 (Box 19)
- Kings County Rural Gazette (Flatbush, New York) (microfilm), January 8, 1876 – September 7, 1878 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Kings County Rural Gazette (Flatbush, New York), May 4, 1878 - 1881 (Box 47)
  Fragile
- Kings County Rural and Brighton Gazette (Flatbush, New York) (microfilm), January 7, 1882 – October 3, 1885 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Kings Courier (eighteen bound volumes), January 2001 - December 2004 (Volume Library gallery shelf 30.1.G)
- Kings Courier (five bound volumes), 2005 (Volume Library gallery shelf 31.1.F)
- Laiks, November 1987 (Box 56)
  Latvian language
- Liberator, 1837, 1840, 1854 (Box 48)
  Abolitionist newspaper
- Linewaiters Gazette, July 1999 (Box 39)
  Park Slope Food Coop newsletter
- Long Island Democrat (Jamaica, New York) (microfilm), May 1835 – September 1912 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Long Island Farmer (Jamaica, New York) (microfilm), 1821-1832; 1873-1900 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Long Island Heritage, May 1983 (Box 39)
- Long Island Star (Brooklyn, New York) (microfilm), June 18, 1809 – June 1863 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Long Island Star (Brooklyn, New York) (one bound volume), 1812-1835 (Box 49)
- Long Island Star (Brooklyn, New York) (one bound volume), January 1827 - January 1829 (Volume 1)
- Long Island Times Weekly (Flushing, New York) (microfilm), January 3, 1861 – December 27, 1877 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Long Island Times Weekly (Flushing, New York) (microfilm), November 7, 1878 – December 24, 1885 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Long Island Times Weekly (Flushing, New York) (microfilm), April 4, 1896 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Long Island Weekly Star (Long Island City, New York) (microfilm), January 2, 1880 – August 4, 1882 (Cabinet Microfilm)
- Long Island Weekly Star (Long Island City, New York) (microfilm), January 4, 1884 – December 25, 1896 (Cabinet Microfilm)